Hey, John. Um, just need you to-- I always forget. I
either have to invite you or you have to, uh, invite
to speak. There we go. Brilliant.
Hey, John. Cool. Is that working? Yes. Is it on yet,
man? Doing web- Okay. It's on. Uh, we doing webcams?
I am giving permissions. Yes, we're doing webcams.
Brilliant. So much, uh, so much handsome energy on
this call now. So, um, we've had a-- we've had some
really good RealFi, um, office hours actually, uh,
since, uh, since you last did the AMA.
We've had, um, product marketing, engineering, data,
and we put out a blog actually, um, to recap all of
those office hours. So this is a, a culmination in
kind of going through the different teams and the
functions.
Um, so John, if everyone... And I'm, I'm sort of
giving a couple of minutes so people can join. Um,
but give us a little bit of an introduction and your
origin story into RealFi. Uh, we've done that with
everybody so far, and then we'll get into some of
the mainnet readiness,
Cardano, and what comes next. I'm kind of intrigued
what everyone else said. I know I've had calls
across, uh, some of these sessions. I need to go and
listen to what, what everyone said, uh, how they,
how I lured them into, into RealFi.
Um, I don't know. I think I've been sort of playing
around with this idea in many different forms for,
like, a very long time. Uh, I think I've always been
interested in two things since I started working in
crypto.
Um, maybe I'll start with that, how I started
working in crypto. Uh, I kind of fell into it. I
met, um, the then chairman of the Cardano
Foundation, Michael Parsons, uh, in like a coffee
shop in Northwest London.
And, uh, to me he was like maybe, uh, a slightly
strange older man that was trying to talk to me.
And, uh, he was asking me what I did. And I worked
in, um, I was working in tech in London in product
and business roles.
And, uh, this was a, a time I suppose when not
everyone really did know what crypto was, and he was
like, uh, "Oh, do you know what crypto is?" I was
like, "Yeah, you know, I read the Bitcoin paper, I
read the Ethereum white paper." Uh, and he was like,
"Oh my God.
Thank God." Um, because, you know, he was nominally
in charge of setting up the Cardano Foundation and I
think, uh, was, was kind of a bit scared over what
entailed. So I joined then.
Um, I did a lot of stuff then, um, back in the day
at Cardano Foundation. I was kind of head of
strategy, head of ecosystem. Um, did a lot of the
initial marketing, um, narratives, and then a lot of
the ecosystem and community set up, and then a lot
of the strategy.
Uh, a whole mix of stuff. Um, and then anyway, uh,
across the sort of work I was doing in Africa, I got
really interested in seeing all these balances
increase. Balances of Bitcoin, balances of Ethereum,
and then, you know, with Tether, balances of USDT.
Um, and really the only thing I could see people
using it for was to, to like either get out of a
trade, say you sell from Bitcoin to at least to
dollars, versus selling to Eth, right?
You're like, "Oh shit, my Bitcoin's going down. Let
me, let me swap to Eth," right? Yeah. When they're
pretty much moving one to one with each other. So
that was a wild time actually before you could
switch out to dollars.
Um, and yeah, mostly what people were using Tether
for was to, like, borrow against their Bitcoin to go
and buy more Bitcoin, which is great, right? There's
nothing wrong with that. Um- Yeah...
but, uh, it did start making me think, um, we've got
these huge and growing balances of dollars, um, what
else could we do with it? Um, you know, the reason
why everyone was just doing crypto stuff is 'cause
no one had really built this bridge to be able to go
and start using that capital to access assets
outside of crypto. There's a whole variety of boring
reasons why that was the case, and a lot of them
have gotten a lot easier. Um, so for me it was,
like, seeing that opportunity and then also, um,
seeing both in emerging markets and in developed
markets, you know, lots of really great fixed income
opportunities where you can, in my view, you know,
earn a very solid risk-adjusted yield, and thinking,
"Okay, well, what if we could pull all of these
things together?
Then we could create more utility in the crypto
space where people's dollars can do more productive
things." But then in the real world space we can
also go and, you know, drive economic growth,
opportunity, all of these other things.
Of course, it's easier to say than it is to do.
There's a lot of risk management, legal set up, a
whole bunch of stuff around that. Um, but that's
kind of how, you know, I was thinking about RealFi.
It took me a while to actually put it together. Um,
funnily enough, I actually didn't want to set this
up. Um, there was another guy I knew who I thought
would be really good, so I was trying to persuade
him to go and, uh, set it up and go and be the CEO.
Uh, unfortunately, it didn't work out that way, so
I'm the shmuck who's, who's had to go and do it. Um,
and that's kind of how, that's kind of how it's
happened. You know, multi-year journey. Um, but we
are here.
We're excited. Um, there's a lot that, um, I won't
be able to talk about, but there's a lot I can talk
about today, so hopefully, um, hopefully we can go
through some of that. And is it-- If I had to
summarize that in two words, it's,
it's interface and infrastructure. Is that fair?
Well, those are your words, Dan, so. Those are my
words. Yeah. I'm, I'm exploring it because I'm
thinking about interfaces with the, with the
ecosystem and you describing, you know, the real
world assets or there's kind of, um, credit or,
uh, assets outside of crypto back when you were
talking to Parsons. And so there just seemed to be
kind of like a wor- two worlds that were not
connected, and so I was thinking about it being an
interface.
But yeah, I'm putting words in your mouth now, John,
so it's not that. Yeah. Well, I know it can be. I
mean, like, I'm not sure whether you guys follow
what ha- what's happening on Hyperliquid and just
how insane its growth is. Um- Yeah...
and look, at the end of the day, people could say a
lot of, talk a lot of smack about crypto, but you
know, there's a reason that as Hyperliquid adds a
bunch of real world assets that you're seeing
volumes that you don't even see in some of the
world's largest traditional exchanges.
'Cause a lot was done right. There's a lot cool with
DeFi. There's a lot cool with twenty-four/seven
settlement, programmatic everything. Like, there's a
lot there. Um, and being able to use your positions
as collateral in other positions.
Like a lot of cool stuff's been done. Um, and for
me, similar to what Hyperliquid, you've seen on
Hyperliquid as they're adding in gold, oil, futures,
all of this kind of stuff, um, we're trying to do
something similar, um, but, you know, with maybe
something or maybe a product that in my view is
maybe more useful for normies, right? Than, um, than
what you're seeing with that kind of stuff.
Okay, cool. But I'm just gonna go, I'm just gonna go
off, um... Actually, I won't even go off camera. I'm
just gonna go close my door. One second.
Okay. While John's going to close his door, um,
we're gonna cover mainnet readiness. There's sort of
three broad, uh, themes that, uh, we might go
through, John, if I got it right. I think we might
be talking about mainnet readiness.
Um, what are the other things that we're gonna
cover?
Um, well, mainnet readiness, what does mainnet
actually mean on Cardano? Like, what can you do, um,
once we're launched? Um, then what comes afterwards,
EVM expansion, broader GTM, um, and, uh,
then you've got some questions from the community.
Yes, we do. Okay, cool. So walk me through mainnet
readiness. What does that look like? Where would you
say- Uh, we're close to ready.
So, uh, thank you everyone for all of the, the
support with testnet, and we've been squashing bugs,
um, you know, uh, taking feedback, adding, adding
features I think for the last few weeks now.
Um, in terms of where we are, we are, we believe,
ready technologically in terms of smart contracts,
all the rest of it, the product. Um, we are
finishing basically the onboarding with our,
like, TradFi providers. So I'll just break that down
a little bit. The way in which we're set up in
RealFi is you've got all of the on-chain stuff, and
behind that you have a set of assets.
Some of those assets are tokenized, like tokenized
money market funds, tokenized T-bills, and then some
of them are off-chain things as well, right? And for
those off-chain things, you need to have a regulated
exchange.
We're actually using StoneX. And then, um, also
we've got some of our own direct lending private
credit stuff. So, uh, because some of this sort of
reaches out into TradFi stuff, um, it's a little bit
slower than you'd like, so we needed to submit, for
instance,
our CIMA registration in the Cayman Islands. You
need to give that to the exchange, StoneX, before
they'll even start setting up the account. So a lot
of these things have to happen sequentially, and we
are doing all of those things.
So, um, we will be ready, um, we're currently
testing out RealFi with real money. Um, there's
about 100K, uh, USD that we've minted, um, that
we're just moving through all of the different, uh,
like venues, wallets, et cetera, um, quite boringly
called hardening. So we're in the hardening phase
with real money. Uh, and then we'll be looking to go
to mainnet.
So approximately, I think mainnet date's gonna be
mid-September. Um, we will give a firm date as we
close out some of the items that we've got in
basically in the next two weeks.
Um, but frankly, it's a long, long, long li- long,
long list of dependencies, um, but we're shredding
through them, so I think it's a realistic timeframe.
Okay, great. Um, um, is there anything else that
needs to happen before la- uh, before the launch, or
that pretty much covers it?
Well, that kind of moves us on to, I think, what you
can do on mainnet. Um, so there are a few things
which I think, uh, we'll see. Um, one is that we are
opening a product in Liqwid.
Uh, it's a pretty cool product where you'll be able
to deposit your ADA, borrow against it, come into
USDr, stake your USDr. Um, so basically a product
that we've designed where people who hold ADA don't
need to sell it to come and participate in
RealFi. So that's something we're excited to launch.
You'll be hearing more about that soon, um, with
Liqwid. Uh, the second sort of launch piece for
Cardano is, uh, with Sundae, um, so we're looking to
take advantage of their new linear swap
feature, um, for Sundae. Is it V2 or V3? I can't
remember. Anyway, Sundae are in version plus 1, um,
which they're working on and, uh, are gonna be
launching at some point.
So that's a cool new feature, which they're
shipping, I think, early for us. Um, so you'll be
able to, you know, go onto Sundae, swap, and then,
uh, take a, you know, either just stake natively
through our application or be able to go and do
something pretty cool with your ADA on
Liqwid. So those are kind of our launch applications
for, um, Cardano. I think shortly we'll actually be
adding those into the testnet so you guys can play
around with that, with, uh, test ADA and test USDr.
Um, and then, yeah, those are, those are kind of our
launch primitives for Cardano. Uh, for anyone
listening, I'm dropping some links in chat just to
save you looking for...
If you haven't heard of them, um, which they are.
And if you've got any questions for John as we're
talking, uh, just put them into the chat- Yeah...
and we can work through them towards the end. Yeah.
Yeah, please do. Please go ahead. I find myself
talking, talking too much.
So, please, if you've got any, any questions, throw
them in. Um, what I'll also just add in, 'cause
everyone's interested in this, um, yeah, in the same
way that, you know, we've been offering points for
the testnet, of course as we move into the mainnet
there'll also be a
points system and season, um, particularly around,
you know, those kind of two venues which, uh, I've
just discussed. Um, so yeah. Um, come, come, come
join.
Uh, 参加者A's asking if one of the cr- if one of the
credit assets in the portfolio defaults- Mm... can
you go through the protection mechanisms for USDr or
sUSDr holders?
Yes. Um, I've been working very hard on this. Um, we
will-- I still need to, uh, I'll-- I can't, like,
fully confirm this, um, but, uh, shortly I will be
able to.
Um, but what you'll essentially have is some level
of de-risking, which is essentially an equity
buffer, um, which gets eaten into first. So within
the portfolio, you have an expectation of credit
losses like you would
normally do within a lo- a loan portfolio. Um, and
then those credit losses are basically built into,
uh, before you get yield, right? It's basically you
subtract those e- those expected credit losses.
And then past that, what you've got is essentially
this equity buffer, which goes first, and this will
be money that I've raised specifically to provide
coverage on this.
Then after that, you have the protocol, um,
basically the protocol reserve. So this gets built
across time. This isn't available on day one, which
is why, you know, going to raise equity for that,
for that first part.
And across time, uh, the sort of order at which the
protocol makes money is that you fund certain things
first. So you fund the stability fund first before,
you know,
the protocol can sort of, um, you know, create, uh,
residual income. Um, so that's kind of the, the way
that you do it. Similar to someone like Ethena, um,
but yeah, as I say, the important part is that
we're, we're trying to build in,
you know, to go and raise to be able to bring in
some de-risking for that. Uh, so I mean, obviously
what I haven't talked about here is, uh, all the
reasons why things should go wrong. That's actually
where you have to spend the majority of your time.
But in the case, of course, that things do, um,
there'll be some basically some protections built in
on that side. Um, what I will say, I think it's
important to also be clear on, there is essentially
a loss waterfall, right?
So after that equity buffer, after the protocol
stability, um, fund gets eaten out of, um, let's say
that you, you still have losses. What would
essentially happen is that you would, um, mark down
the sUSDr number.
So sUSDr people would be hit first, and then finally
it would be USDr holders. So that's kind of like the
cascading order of what happens or the loss
waterfall as things go wrong.
Um, as I say, we'll be spending a lot of time
hopefully to make sure that, that, that doesn't
happen. Um, but we do have a transparent
subordination basically, um, seniority, uh, level
over who gets hit when.
Hmm. Um, 参加者B's asking, uh, "Is RealFi gonna run
directly on top of Cardano, or is RealFi its own
chain or a fork of Cardano?" It runs--It's adapter,
it runs, it runs directly on Cardano.
Um, you know, we've got our native assets on, uh,
which you can actually, you can actually see these.
Um, we're actually on Cexplorer now, so you can see
USDr.
Um- Oh, nice. Yeah. So yeah, that's, that's how we
operate, and then we are doing something clever for
the EVM side. So, um, Cardano will still sit as like
the canonical source of truth and the accounting
layer, um,
and then we'll burn a mint basically, um, to be able
to issue also natively on Ethereum, and that's
pretty much a fork of CCTP, Circle's Cross-Chain
Transfer Protocol, um, that we've been using will
likely shift over to LayerZero
once it arrives on Cardano. But the cool thing about
this setup, right, is that as even if you have loads
and loads and loads of demand on EVM and Pendle and,
you know, Aave, blah, blah, blah- Mm.
Uh, you'll still be growing the stablecoin balance
on Cardano because that's kind of where the asset
sit. So, um, yeah, so even, you know, cool stuff
happening on Ethereum, uh, can still drive the,
the overall, uh, stablecoin supply on Cardano, which
is kind of a nice externality. And then, um, Alpha
Growth also won their proposal, which I'm very happy
about. Yeah. Um, so I think that's also a huge
opportunity for us.
I think we're building a great product here, and I
think that with the investment that Alpha Growth
will be able to coordinate now across, you know,
some of the projects that exist on Cardano, I think
we've got a really good shot of, uh, of building,
really building some, some DeFi TVL. Um, they've
been working-- I know they've been speaking to
everyone, telling them what they need to change to
their protocols to be able to get them up to scratch
and to be able to get LPs from across the crypto
ecosystem, not just Cardano people to participate.
Um, they should have a chunky incentives budget. So
yeah, I think that could be really cool. Sorry, I,
I, I, I kind of went off that, but, um, hopefully
it- No, I think it was interesting.
Uh, just to, just to make sure that I haven't done
something silly, I've put the USDr, uh, link in
Cexplorer into the chat. Is that the correct one,
John? 'Cause I know sometimes people create arte--
you know, fake ones, so I just wanna make sure I'm
giving people the right link.
Uh, I don't know. Thank you. Let me look.
And while you're looking, uh, 参加者A is asking,
"What's the minimum amount of ADA required?" Yeah,
we've said, 参加者A, the minimum amount of ADA
required for delegation to earn rewards isn't gonna
be disclosed 'cause there are anti-sybil,
anti-farming measures in place.
So providing that information only makes it easy for
people to, to b- to farm. So yeah, anti-sybil
measures are a bit trust us, bro. Which is gonna--
any good faith actors will be fine.
People that are trying to optimize of zero, zero
point- balances, uh, are not. Um, okay Thank you
for, thanks for reminding me, Ben, that I'm not
supposed to say that Yeah Yeah Um, okay,
so USDr. Um, is that the right link, John? Yeah
Okay, cool. Uh, so what, what comes next after
Cardano mainnet? Oh, did we cover wallets?
I think we talked about launch apps, which was
great. Uh, what are the wallets that are gonna be
ready at launch?
Um, Lace, um, is the primary partner, um, we're
working f- with. Um, but ultimately it's a, you
know, it's a native token, so you should be able to
hold it anywhere, right?
Yeah. Okay, so, um- I suppose the better answer is
that, the better answer is we've been working with
Lace on building, like, a specific really, hopefully
really nice experience for you to be able to swap
in, out, stake, uh,
like really trying to make it super simple and super
nice. Uh, you know, like we've been saying a lot,
uh, you know, we just, we just want, like, one
button, right?
So we wanna turn complexity into simplicity, and I
think that I got Lace and I can't even link my main
wallet.
Yeah, well, um, um, I hope they fix that for you.
Uh, so, uh, anyway, like it's, it's the first
experience that we're building. Um, I actually, it's
interesting, so Lace, Lace is working really well
for me now.
Um, it, I'm not gonna say it always does, but it's
working really nicely now.
Um, and then- Yeah... sorry, what, where, where were
we, Ben? Uh, we were about to jump into, um, uh, we
talked about Cardano mainnet and we were gonna talk
about what comes next, maybe other cross-chain, um,
endeavors, uh, but then I dragged us back. Uh, 参加者C
is asking about a LayerZero, which I haven't, um,
thought about. He says, "As a builder what is the
current state of LayerZero to leverage it from your
perspective?" I don't- Yeah...
have any updates on So I, yeah, I was, I was quite
concerned by this actually a while ago, right? In
that- Mm... um, when I was first designing, thinking
about this, there wasn't really an easy way to get
USDC from Eth or EVM
world over to Cardano, um, um, back. Um, the USDCx
bridge has actually made that a lot easier, um, we
can use a lot of the technology there to basically
stand up, stand up a bridge that doesn't require
you, like,
holding lots of assets locked and creating a
honeypot, um, and is also based on very robust, uh,
yeah, very robust work from Circle. That being said,
I mean, I'd rather, yeah, I'd rather we,
we shift to LayerZero. So my understanding is that
it's coming towards the end of the year. Um, so we
basically architected everything, that it's easy for
us to switch out that messaging layer.
Uh, so when it's available, we'll just, just shift
essentially the messaging layer and shift over to
that.
That's great. Thank you, John. Um, so walk us
through what comes next, um, either after or
concurrently, uh, with the Cardano mainnet.
Okay. So, um, for me, there's like two-- it's like,
it's like a Cardano sandwich. So we'll start with
our Cardano launch, and then we're going to have,
um, a lot of EVM stuff.
Um, so typically that's going to be around
increasing distribution, um, through venues. We
wanna obviously have more venues, more people to be
able to access the product. Uh, but it's also
working with curators for them to set up vaults
with specific strategies and build deep liquidity,
uh, for people to be able to do cool things. So this
could be some of these levered looping strategies.
For those people who aren't familiar with it, uh,
it's like kind of, it's kind of a simple idea.
If you're getting, and this is not a promise of
return, let's just hypothetically, let's say you
were getting 8.5%, um, with sUSDr. So you go, you
put $100 in, you stake it, you've got sUSDr now.
Uh, then you borrow against that position, and
depending on what rate people will lend you normal
dollars, let's say USDC. Let's say they're lending
it to you at 5% against your possession, you can
then go get more USDr, stake it,
and then, um, basically do this again. So this is
leverage. And, uh, it's what crypto people call
looping. Um, we've renamed leverage as looping, um,
but that's essentially what that is.
And the cool thing about our product is that where
this goes really badly wrong is of, of course, if
the underlying asset is volatile. Um, so in our
view, fixed income's kind of a appropriate asset
class for this.
So we're hoping that we should be an attractive
option for people to set up and manage looping
strategies. Um, and in the EVM world, that's really,
really big. So we'll be looking to get a curator, go
and set up some vaults for us, um, so people can
access the product there.
And then, uh, the sort of other part of the
sandwich, the last piece of bread, um, we'll be
coming back to, uh, start working with Alpha Growth
and all of the venues on Cardano, who should have,
uh, basically had that time to be able to do some
upgrades to
their protocols, get some additional audits, Alpha
Growth to start crowding in additional LPs. Um, so
that's kind of the, the very vanilla summary. Um,
the one thing, of course, that I can't talk about is
specific listings or anything like that.
So, um, yeah, um, you'll know more when, when we can
talk about that kind of thing. There was a really
good question the other- One of the other calls and,
uh, you would've been the guy to answer it at the
time.
Um, it was about basically how do you price like,
um, a private credit or a debt that doesn't have a,
a s- an established price, and I think you'd
explained it to me once and I thought it might be
good just to cover that if you know what I'm
referring to.
Yeah. I mean, look, you can price it... So you can
price it in terms of, like, the actual coupon,
right? So what are you going to go and get paid? And
then you can discount by basically expected,
expected losses in a portfolio.
The issue is, is that, and this is, this is
essentially a fundamental issue with these kinds of
assets is, like, what if something goes wrong,
right? So from that perspective on your crypto
dashboards, et cetera, it would still be increasing,
like,
monotonically by the expected increase from the
interest rate, but maybe something's actually gone
wrong in the real world and it's not being
reflected, and that's actually where we've seen some
of the blow-ups, I think, in crypto recently around
that, those kind of products.
So third party attestation is the answer. You're
gonna have someone who's not you go and look at it
and value it. Um, it's not that cheap, but it's
still kind of required, and I also think not just
for us, I think for all people trying to bring real
world assets
into crypto, it's going to become even more
important, um, because whilst, you know, we, we have
a fund administrator who will report the net asset
value of the portfolio.
For them, they're not gonna report fake figures, but
if you think about the assets that are being held,
it's very easy for them to price a very large CLO
ETF that's traded globally.
It's very easy for them to price T-bills, right? And
there's no way you could go to them and say, "Oh,
I've got a different T-bill rate from you. Um, can
you use my rate?" But for these harder to value
assets, um, they're not specialists in that.
So I think that sort of third party attestation at
different periods is really important, and to be
quite boring about it, it's what traditional TradFi
does, right?
They, they s- they've been doing this for a very
long time. I think it's just in crypto, um, we're a
bit newer to some of this stuff. I'm not sure
whether anyone's seen this, but there's been quite a
few issues over a firm, I think it's called, like,
Accountable, um, or, um...
Yeah, something like Accountable. Anyway, they-
they've been responsible for basically providing the
verification on a number of projects they've been
using, so the real world asset stuff that have all
paused, um, paused their, uh, redemptions recently
and it's because I think people are
treating... You know, you need to do some actual
work to be able to go and value this stuff, right?
It's not just like a dashboard and asking people to
fill out a survey. So anyway, it's a long-winded
answer, but third party verification is really
important, um,
people who aren't us doing it.
Mm. Um, and- There's lots of questions in the chat
here. Do you think maybe, Ben, we just, we just run
through a couple of these quickly? Yeah, let's do
that. Yeah. So 参加者C has asked, "When does sUSDr...
When sUSDr is sitting on an exchange in an open
trade position, is it earning yield?
And if yes, will this yield automatically increase
the stake on the exchange position?" Depends on your
exchange. Um, uh, there are different ways in which
different, uh, CEXs handle this.
Um, for some CEXs, the answer is yes. Um, for some,
maybe the answer is no. Um, for some, the answer can
be, um, you know, they'll only hold, uh, the
unstaked version, um,
and expect, um, basically rewards to be paid to
them. There's, like, a whole mix of models in this
industry about how people do things. Uh, 参加者C, what
you've put there is basically the key use case that,
um, I'm trying to close.
Uh, what I'd really like is for people to be able to
hold sUSDr on an exchange, to be able to use that as
collateral against other positions whilst it's
accruing in value.
I think that's a killer use case of basically, um,
NAV accruing or accreting collateral. Uh, so yeah,
that's, that's what you've described is the good
example over how things would work with an exchange
who wants to support
that.
Uh, 参加者D is asking Um, yeah Sorry. Uh, is it gonna
be possible to jump in for more SPOs to support the
RealFi? I think we're still in the planning stages.
Still wanting maybe one, one for you, Ben. Yeah, I
mean, fundamentally I'm building out a case, uh, for
what could lo- what that could l- look like beyond
the main net.
So I'm deep in the weeds with product and marketing
and submitting ideas to John, but, uh, it's not
signed off, so, um, it's still in progress. So 参加者A's
asking estimates regarding which CEXs.
We've already said that we can't say, and, um,
whether USDr is gonna meet, uh, MiCA requirements or
Genius, but those are, uh, geo-restricted locations,
right, John?
Yeah, we're not currently, um, looking to, um, to,
to support that standard, um, for a whole bunch of
reasons.
Um, I wish we could.
The next question from 参加者B, well, it's more an
offer, but DeFi Llama is working on off-chain as-
attestations. Mm. Um, can make intros for us if
we're interested.
So shall I follow up on that? Yeah, that would be
cool. I'm... We've been working with Token Terminal,
um, who I think pushed through maybe to DeFi Llama.
Um, I think we've spoken to them maybe a while ago.
Um, but yeah, I think that could be cool. Um, maybe
Ben just checking whether, um, 同僚A wants to
reach out. Yeah. But yeah, I think, you know, just
on, on that front, 参加者F, uh, you've, you've
definitely seen that, like the way in which they
account for, uh,
off-chain reserves is like changed quite a lot I
think on DeFi Llama. Um, 'cause it's kind of a
nightmare for them, right? Their whole product is
like transparency over, you know, real data feeds,
and then you've got this thing that's, uh,
completely off-chain, which can really bite you if,
uh, if it's not being done properly. So, yeah.
Really good. Uh- Um, so I'm gonna switch just- Yeah,
go on... oh, we've got questions that came in from
the form, so I wanna make sure we hit those as well.
Um- Yeah... so what challenges...
Now if we've covered some of this already, then
just, uh, slap my hand, but what challenges does
USDr face across different countries, and what pre-
preparations or measures are needed? And a related
question that came in was what legal entity
structures give a project the best global reach
across US,
UK, and EU? So a mix there, John, but how do you
wanna approach it?
Um, yeah, I think it's less about the structure and
more about what you're trying to do. Um, so you...
Before you decide on like where you wanna structure
something, you decide on the activities that you're
trying to do.
Um, part of this, right, over where, how, whether
you'll get coverage in particular countries is also
not really in your control. So obviously the stuff
moving in the US over CLARITY Act is, is kind of
highly relevant for us.
Um, yeah, it was delayed again, again recently. You
know, a lot of this comes down to stuff that's
bigger than you, right? So the kind of fight in the
US between crypto, um, firms kind of becoming banks,
and banks realizing that risk and really not wanting
that to happen, and that being fought in the houses
in, in the US. Like that's not really about us,
right? But, um, ultimately we built a product that
we believe will be able to get enough global
distribution to be, to be interesting.
Um, what, you know, what I'm not really interested
in doing is changing the product completely, um, to
match one particular jurisdiction, like let's say
the, the US.
Maybe later on if we get big, we can look at, you
know, doing a version for that particular market.
Um, but, you know, there's lots of people who have
offered T-bill based products already.
You don't, you don't really need another one of
those. Um, so yeah, we're trying to do something a
bit different and, um, make stable coins a bit more
productive and hopefully, um, create also a better
product for users.
And sometimes that means that there's particular
geos that, um, you're not going to be, you're not
gonna be appropriate for, and that's okay.
Okay, the next question, I'm not 100% sure if it's
RealFi specific or they're more asking you broadly,
so we'll do both maybe, right? Um, are there
upcoming features or product launches that you're
particularly excited about for RealFi and then more
generally? Hmm. Um, for RealFi, I think vaults. I
think that, you know, there's a couple of things
that vault curators do for you.
They don't just set it up and help bring in LPs and
set parameters, um, but they also kind of act as a
third party, um, kind of like a fund manager, right?
They kind of manage risk and due diligence and
stuff.
I think that's like a really important credibility
check for us. Um, so getting a vault set up, um, I
think is really important, um, and something I'm
very excited for.
So that's probably like the first part. Um,
secondly, uh, I've had... I'm starting to have some
conversations with, quote unquote, "real
businesses." So these are people who have dollar
flows for short-ish periods of time and are looking
for
ways to be able to get some additional economics,
um, during that period. Uh, so this isn't
necessarily crypto businesses, but think more like
remittance businesses or, um, things like that.
Um, so trying to see whether there's product market
fit for, you know, USDr and sUSDr in non-crypto
businesses. They might be crypto adjacent, but you
know, people doing real things in the real world,
um, and seeing whether we have product market fit
there.
So I had a, a good conversation today about, uh,
something along that line. So seeing whether we can
get our first like real world customer, you know,
whether that's someone who runs a furniture factory
who has a bunch of dollars across different accounts
and they wanna
use this as a treasury management product, or
whether it's like facilitating remittance flows. Um,
yeah, I think the market's much bigger than just
people chasing yield in crypto.
Um, so yeah, interested to see whether we can get
something there. Um, and then more broadly, I mean,
uh, who isn't excited for the Anthropic IPO? I saw
$2 trillion as a, as a target price.
So, uh, after the SpaceX extravaganza, I'm, I'm
excited to see, to see where we end up with that. I
mean, uh, yeah, people thought crypto had big
numbers, right?
That...
Yes. Um, no, I had a really interesting conversation
yesterday actually with someone I won't name, but
saying that one of the issues with Web3 was that,
um, these L1s were stuck in Web3 economies and
you've gotta get out into other economies.
So I think it kinda echoes what you're saying there.
Um, the next question is, uh, community incentives.
Will early users who actively participated in and
supported Testnet receive exclusive roles, badges,
or other special incentives?
I am discussing that with the team and, um, putting
ideas, and I think 同僚B's got his own ideas too, t-
full credit to him. So yeah, there is a lot of
thinking in that, but I'm not gonna confirm
anything.
Um, Cardano Mainnet is the next question. Cardano
Mainnet integrations, I think you've covered it,
John, but is SundaeSwap going to be an official DEX
for RealFi? Yeah, we'll, we'll be working with,
definitely working with Sundae.
Um, yes.
I don't know what official means. Okay, so- But yes,
we'll be, we'll be working- If, if they're getting-
Maybe officially and unofficially, both. All kinds
of official. Mm-hmm.
Um, okay, so we've gone through, uh, you know, um,
those three core points about mainnet readiness,
mainnet on Cardano, what comes next. We've gone
through the questions that we've had so far.
If anyone's got any questions, put them into chat.
Is there anything you haven't been asked yet, John,
that you wish I'd had the foresight to ask you? Mm.
Is there something we should talk about?
Mm, no, I think, you know, approximate mainnet
dates, what you'll be able to do on Cardano once
we're live, um, kind of how the EVM side's still
gonna grow circulating supply for USDr on Cardano,
um,
some of the cool things happening on EVM, and then
of course how we're gonna bring all of those cool
things to, uh, to Cardano with the Alpha Growth
Proposal. So I think those are probably the big
ones.
And for the benefit of the summary and for people
that weren't on the call, can you just go back and
explain what vaults are and why they're exciting?
Yeah. So vaults are kind of like programmatic
digital funds. So you've got a vault manager, um,
who's responsible for setting the parameters and the
strategies, and then you've got LPs who basically
come into that vault.
Um, ultimately, like, you know, the cool thing
about, I suppose the sort of reason for this being
set up is that you add an extra layer of
accountability on the vault curator or, you know, as
I say in the analogy of the kind of fund manager.
Um, so hopefully if they're doing their job right,
they're gonna set the parameters so you've got only
good assets being added to that, um, and also making
sure that, you know, there's not too much leverage
or whatever in that.
So yeah, they kind of sit as an additional, an, uh,
additional credibility point. I wouldn't say
everything's always gone right in vault world, um,
but, um, uh, you know, they were sort of set up to
solve a problem over some of the nonsense you saw in
DeFi.
And, uh- Mm... yeah, I, I think they d- they're
definitely a- an improvement.
Okay, great. Well, John, I really appreciate you.
Uh, and I genuinely know how busy you are, um,
you're constantly, uh, in calls and working. So
thank you for coming on and spending some time with
us, and we're doing this on rotation, so you'll be
back in about six weeks I think, roughly.
Um, any final words before we wrap up? Yeah, I just
wanna say, like, you know, thank you to all 25 of
you guys who've all tuned in. Um, I see a lot of
familiar names from, uh, from following the Discord.
Um, so yeah, really appreciate everyone, and also
some of the SPOs here. Uh, so yeah, thanks guys. I
think maybe things have been a tiny bit quiet whilst
we've been getting everything set up. Um, I promise
you we're actually busier than ever, um, and we'll
be going towards, uh, mainnet very shortly,
so setting dates and then there'll be a lot more
engagement. Um, so anyway, I do, I'm lurking around
the Discord, uh, um, so yeah, I, it's really great
seeing all of you there.
Brilliant. Thanks everybody. Thank you John. And
yeah, anyone just, uh, ping, ping us if you've got
any further questions. Cheers everybody. Yeah. Bye.